Aaron Marino Full Stack Developer

Greater Raleigh, NC

<u>www.linkedin.com/in/-aaron-marino</u> <u>amarino1979.github.io</u> <u>aaronmarino1979@gmail.com</u> (c)863-604-7242

I am a software engineer with a background in education and curriculum writing. I have 10 years experience in the classroom working with diverse groups of students and adults, collaborative planning, leading professional development opportunities, presentation design, and public speaking.

Skills:

Languages and Frameworks: Javascript, React, Node.js, Express, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap Databases, Management & Deployment: SQLite, MongoDB, Git, GitHub, Heroku, CLI Methodologies: Object Oriented Programming, MVC Pattern, Responsive Design, Authentication

Relevant Experience:

Software Engineer Fellow: General Assembly | May 2020 - Ending mid-August 2020

- Current Fellow in a 12 week software engineering bootcamp with over 500 hours of instruction and projects.
- <u>Project 1</u>: Suburb_Growing App | This app was created to help provide solutions for those who like to have a small garden and want data on popular plants. Technologies used: jQuery, Javascript, API, CSS, HTML
- <u>Project 2</u>: WorkoutXpress_App | Developed a full stack app for designing workouts with user authentication. Technologies used: Javascript, EJS, Node.js, MongoDB, Bootstrap, HTML/CSS
- <u>Project 3</u>: Xpense_App | Group project where 3 of us designed a full stack MERN app that had a
 responsive table to build out and track a budget. Technologies used: MongoDB, Express, React,
 Node.js, Javascript Web Tokens, Bootstrap, HTML/CSS, Insomnia

Experience:

Elementary School Teacher: Oakview Elementary, Wake County, NC & Victory Ridge Academy, Polk County, FL | August 2010 - July 2020 |

- Showed positive growth in student learning gains where I either met or exceeded growth standards in over 80% of students for the last 5 years of teaching.
- Collaborated with a team of 9 first grade teachers to develop relevant curriculum and use best practices when implementing lessons.
- Dedicated 5 years working with special needs students and received teacher of the year twice and had a highly effective rating.
- Recipient of the Duke Energy STEM Grant 2016 & 2017 worth over \$5k.

Freelance Curriculum Writer: Studies Weekly | May 2016 – August 2019 |

- Working in fast paced environments with hard deadlines.
- Developing articles that tie into scope and sequence of state standards, create teacher supplements and all student materials.
- Design and evaluate test questions according to various state standards.

Community Service:

- Site coordinator for F3, help support morning bootcamps for men | Feb. 2020 Present
- Youth leader at Grace Community Church and guitarist | March 2019 Present
- Finance Committee Chair at South Lake Wales Church of God | April 2013 April 2016
- Soccer Coach Fuguay Varina & Lake Wales Soccer Club | 2012-2016 & Spring 2020

Education:

General Assembly | Software Engineer Immersive Bootcamp | Currently Enrolled American College of Education | MA Educational Leadership | July 2018 Warner University | BA Communications / Minor: Biblical Studies | May 2003